surveylot.com 2009-03-06

# Paid Surveys - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

 **By visiting SurveyLot.com you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy.**

SurveyLot respects your privacy! We appreciate the trust you place in us by voluntarily providing information on this web site and we express our commitment to use this information with both care and sensitivity. The types of information collected and how we use it are outlined as follows:

**Personal Information**

Your personal contact and demographic information collected on SurveyLot.com will NOT be shared with third parties, except if required to comply with any applicable laws, regulations, legal process, or governmental request.   
Any information you voluntarily enter on our web site is maintained by SurveyLot to help us improve our web site and your user experience of our services. Your contact information including name and email address may be used by SurveyLot to contact you via email with information regarding services on our website that you have expressed interest in. Based on demographic information collected on our website, including gender, age, zip code, country and IP, SurveyLot can provide you with a more personalized experience and tailor the different products, services, and advertising to your specific profile.    
We may choose to retain other companies or individuals to perform functions consistent with our Privacy Policy on behalf of SurveyLot. Such third parties may be given access to personally identifiable information necessary to provide their functions, but they may not use the information for any other purpose.

**Communications and Opting-out**

SurveyLot does NOT send unsolicited or “spam” email. SurveyLot periodically sends paid survey invitations ONLY to our web site users who during registration opted in their “Preferences” to receive such invitations via email. We may also occasionally send to these opt-in users information regarding our products and services, and targeted advertising which we believe may be of interest to them.  By providing your email address and contact information to SurveyLot and choosing to receive email invitations, you agree to receive periodic e-mail offers from SurveyLot. We respect your privacy and we provide you with several easy ways to unsubscribe at any time from receiving our email communications.  If you do not wish to receive email from SurveyLot, simply do ANY of the following:

a) unselect the “Send me personalized paid survey invitations via email” checkbox in your preferences during registration

b) follow the ‘Change Preferences’ link located on any of your personalized SurveyLot ‘Results’ pages and unselect the checkbox described in a)

c) use the ‘unsubscribe’ (opt-out) link provided at the bottom of each and every SurveyLot email communication sent to you

d) go to our Unsubscribe web page located at <http://www.surveylot.com/unsubscribe.jsp> and enter your email address

**Tell-A-Friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about SurveyLot, we will ask for your and your friend’s name and email address. On your behalf, we will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit SurveyLot.com.  We do not store or use this information in any other way.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. cookies on this site. SurveyLot.com uses both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. We set a persistent cookie to store your account ID, so you don’t have to enter your profile information more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.  If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited. 

**Log Files**

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data.  We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.  We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. 

**Pixel Tags and Tracking Technology**

When you visit SurveyLot or view one of our emails, we may use pixel tags (also known as clear gifs), and tracking links to keep track of some of the pages you visit on our site and personalize your experience. We may also use pixel tags to determine what types of email your browser supports, and if html emails sent to you were opened. We may use the information collected through pixel tags, tracking links and similar technology in combination with your personally identifiable information to provide you with a more personalized experience on our site.

**Links to Other Sites**

SurveyLot.com contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites.  We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.  This privacy statement applies only to information collected by SurveyLot.com. 

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement.    
We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, without prior notification, so please review it frequently. 

**Contact Us**

If you have any concerns about our privacy policy, please send us an e-mail at [support@SurveyLot.com](mailto:support@SurveyLot.com) , and we will make every effort to address your inquiry in a timely manner. 

_Last Modified October 30, 2008_
